## Carlos Mougan

https://cmougan.github.io/ https://www.linkedin.com/in/carlosmougan/

### Professional Summary

I am currently a Statistician Trainee in the European Central Bank, during the last years I have work in diverse research fields such as Artificial Intelligence, Data Science, Meteorology & predictive modeling. I have also experience as a consultant in Deloitte. Also, I have joined numerous data science competitions achieving: 1st Boston Consulting Group Gamma Datathon, 3rd Accenture Health Datathon, 1st at SpainML Telco-churn and Bronze Medal at Kaggle IEEE-CIS Fraud Detection. I have a special interest in data science ethics, & responsible Artificial Intelligence. My professional goal is to have an impact on society through research, innovation and a sense of creativity.

### EXPERIENCE

### European Central Bank

Frankfurt, Germany

Email: carmougan@gmail.com

Mobile: +34 620 618 275

Directorate of Statistics

Jan 2020 - Now

• Statistician - Data Science Trainee: Monitoring the quality of statistics on the balance of payments and international investment position, as well as methods and sources in EU Member States. Developing machine learning and statistical modeling techniques for the National Central Banks. End to end management of a Data Science consulting project.

### The Alan Turing Institute

London, United Kingdom Aug 2019 - Sept 2019

University of Bristol

• Data Science Facilitator: With the Alan Turing Institute and the University of Bristol I was a Data Science Facilitator for the Data Case Study Group with a team of 10 researchers and Data Scientist tackling air pollution and traffic for the Bristol City Council.

## Barcelona SuperComputing Center

Barcelona, Spain

Applied Learning Methods

April 2019 - Aug 2019

• Research Data Scientist: This research line explores the use of Learning Techniques to different domains, from data centre optimization to cancer genomics, leveraging different techniques from statistical Machine Learning to state of the art Deep Learning and Neural Networks, and different programming frameworks.

CSIC-IIIA

Barcelona, Spain

National Research Council - Artificial Intelligence Institute

Jan 2019 - July 2018

• Deep Learning Research Assistant: Improving and applying Generative Adversarial Networks (GANs) to approach large scale combinatorial optimization problems.

## **Deloitte Robotics**

Madrid, Spain

Technological Consultant

Dec 2017 - August 2018

- Team Leader: Coordinated a team of two developers, a machine learning engineer and two data analysts applying Cognitive Automation (CA) to the Audit Process. Implementing Machine Learning to the extraction (OCR) and the classification of unstructured data with WorkFusion. I took part in the delivery of the project where we were able to improve the efficiency and effectiveness of their operations by a 70%.
- UiPath Trainer: UiPath trainer to the international Deloitte's team of Belgium and Netherlands.
- Naoqi Developer: Developing functions for the robots of SoftBank Pepper and Nao for commercial and marketing purposes. We collaborated in events and workshops were Pepper was in charge of 'chairing' and introducing the speakers.
- **Uipath Developer**: Developer for a leading national banking company where we automated two processes. In the delivery of the project we obtained automation of a 100% and an 80% respectively, allowing workers to focus on more creative tasks.

# **AEMET**Agencia Estatal de Meteorología

Madrid, Spain

Sept 2017 - Dec 2017

o **Internship**: at the Prediction and Modelling Department with a University collaboration where I modeled and predicted the atmospheric pollution of the northern side of Italy.

#### EDUCATION

### Universitat Autónoma de Barcelona

Barcelona, Spain

Master in Mathematical Modelling: Data Science

 $Sept.\ 2018-Jul\ 2019$ 

### Universidad Complutense de Madrid

Madrid, Spain

Degree in Physics

Sept. 2013 - Feb 2018

 $\circ \ \mathbf{Specialized} \ \mathbf{in} \ \mathbf{Atmospheric} \ \mathbf{Physics} \ \mathbf{and} \ \mathbf{Astrophysics} \ : \ \mathbf{Dissertation} \ \mathbf{in} \ \mathbf{'Atmospheric} \ \mathbf{Contamination} \ \mathbf{Modelling'}.$ 

## Saint Paul Preparatory High School

Minnesota, US

International baccalaureate

• Honor International Student at Saint Paul Preparatory: Received a Scholarship for international students with an excellent curriculum (€10,000).

## OTHER INFORMATION

- Languages: Spanish(Native), English (Fluent, C1).
- Volunteering with Refugees(Athens) April 2017: Volunteering experience working alongside war refugees trying to improve their environment
- Elite Swimming Athlete 2013 -2017: National recognition for athletes with an outstanding performance. Achievements: Finalist of the Spanish Olympic Trials 2016, 3<sup>rd</sup> Team in Spanish Honor Division, 2012 Minnesota State Champions as Individual & Team. Record holder of several state events.